#### **Fernando Sotano Camilo**

Full Stack Developer

Address 206 Great Western Street, M14 4LH, Manchester, UK

Mobile +44 07727002790

E-mail <u>fscamilo@alumni.usp.br</u>

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/fernando-sotano-camilo-81b3b919/

#### **SUMMARY:**

Started working as a software developer in 1994, having experience in several languages such as C, Pascal, VBA, HTML, PHP and JavaScript for web and desktop development. Graduated in Electrical Engineering in 2006, started working as a SmartPlant Instrumentation consultant in the oil and gas sector and innovated the data presentation from instrumentation projects with VBA applications and SQL queries. In 2019 moved back to web development working as a Full Stack developer. Currently experienced in PHP, Laravel, JavaScript, MySQL, JQuery, CSS and HTML. Had good exposure to Bootstrap, Python, Java and AngularJS for personal projects. Full command of Windows, Linux, Git, Microsoft Office and Adobe Photoshop in an accumulated 25 years overall computing experience.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Bachelor in Electrical Engineering**

Polytechnic School of the University of São Paulo, São Paulo, Brazil.

Emphasis on power systems and electrical automation.

Professor Áurio Falcone Prize for the best graduation project in 2005 at the Department of Electrical Energy and Automation Engineering with the Design and Construction of a Rotary Torque Transducer.

## **Data Processing Technician**

State Technical School Professor Camargo Aranha, São Paulo, Brazil.

Programming and data processing.

### **WORK EXPERIENCES**

### Senior PHP Developer – Harper James, Manchester, United Kingdom.

June 2019 - Current

- Full Stack Web Development
- Backend development with PHP, Laravel and MySQL.
- Frontend development with HTML, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap and CSS.
- Designed and developed an e-commerce website for a plants store from scratch.

## Software Developer - NQC, Manchester, United Kingdom.

January 2019 - June 2019

- Full Stack Web Development
- Backend development with PHP and MySQL.
- Frontend development with HTML, JavaScript, JQuery and CSS.
- Fixed bugs and added new features for a supply chain online system.

## Software Engineer - Agorà S.R.L., Milan, Italy.

February 2018 - October 2018

- Extraction, transforming and loading large amounts of data from engineering projects to database.
- Analysis of large amounts of data to find inconsistences and improvements to the project.
- Excel VBA programming for data cleaning and reporting.
- Complex SQL queries development.
- Consulting for Intergraph SmartPlant Instrumentation over Microsoft SQL Server database.

## Software Engineer - Tomeferrostaal Consortium, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.

September 2012 - November 2016

- Analysis and manipulation of large amounts of data to find inconsistences and potential improvements to the project.
- Development of SQL queries and Excel VBA macros for report generation, based on Oracle data, reducing the time of the generation of instrument lists, cable lists and others to a few seconds.
- Development of Excel VBA macros to strongly reduce time of activities not only related to SPI, but also for general project automation purposes.
- Administration of SmartPlant Instrumentation software for instrumentation projects over Oracle database. Performed all software procedures on the detailing project of eight oil platforms.

# Software Engineer - Doris Engineering, Rio de Janeiro, Brazil.

April 2011 – September 2012

- Development of SQL queries and Excel VBA macros for database comparison among SPI, SPP&ID and SP3D.
- Administration of SmartPlant Instrumentation software for instrumentation projects over Oracle database. Performed all software procedures on the detailing project of eight oil platforms.
- Performed consistence check and correction, import of data, customization of specification sheets and report generation using Smartplant and Infomaker.
- Supported and trained users on FEED phase of a project of eight oil platforms for Brazilian pre-salt exploration.

# Software Engineer - Sisgraph, São Paulo, Brazil.

September 2006 - November 2008

- Supported Intools and Smartplant Instrumentation users in all software modules.
- Trained customers in many states of Brazil.
- Helped customers for implementation, integration with other applications and problems solution.

# PHP Developer - CCE (Centre of computing of the University of São Paulo), São Paulo, Brazil.

June 2002 - June 2004

- PHP/MySQL development.
- Development of a system for managing network issues in the university campus.

#### **LANGUAGE SKILLS**

- English
- Portuguese (native)
- Italian

#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT SKILLS

- Work experience in PHP, Laravel, JavaScript, MySQL, HTML, CSS, JQuery, Ajax, SQL and VBA.
  Procedural and Object Oriented Programming using MVC architecture.
- Academic or home experience in Java, Python, C, Pascal and others.
- Microsoft Office including advanced Excel with VBA, SVN, Git, Linux, Photoshop.